tripdatabase.com 2017-07-12

# Privacy - Trip Database

NOTE: At the foot of this page is a privacy policy by our advertising partners UBM Medica, please read.

1 Introduction

1.1 TRIP Database takes the privacy of your information very seriously. This policy explains how and for what purposes we use the information collected about you via www.tripdatabase.com (referred to below as the “Site”). Please read this privacy policy carefully. By using the Site and any services we offer via the Site, you are agreeing to be bound by this policy in respect of the information collected about you via this Site.

1.2 If you have any queries about the policy, please get in touch with us using the contact details set out www.tripdatabase.com and we will do our best to answer your questions.

2 Personal information collected

2.1 We will collect the following personal information from you:

2.1.1 name, a user name;

2.1.2 e-mail address;

2.1.3 country

2.1.4 profession and/or clinical speciality.

2.1.5 Keywords of interest

2.2 General information such as your opinions upon articles read and/or contributed to.

2.3 Collation of the above information is only compulsory when you register via My-TRIP

3 Use of this information

3.1 We will use this information in order to:

3.1.1 send you information about our products and services;

3.1.2 allow others to view your comments/opinions on articles written or read. For the avoidance of doubt the information displayed will not contain your personal information as set out in clause 2.1 above

4 Sharing this information

4.1 We do not share your information with any third parties other than as set out in clause 3.1.2 above

5 Information automatically collected from your computer

5.1 Log files/IP addresses: When you visit the Site our web server automatically records your IP address. This IP address is not linked to any of your personal information.

6 Cookies

6.1 When you visit the Site we may store some information (commonly known as a “cookie”) on your computer. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your hard drive to store and sometimes track information about you. Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot be accessed by other servers, which means that they cannot be used to track your movements around the web. Passwords and credit card numbers are not stored in cookies. A cookie helps you get the best out of the Site and helps us to provide you with a more customised service. We use cookies for the following purposes:

6.1.1  we use cookies to track how our site is used and to improve and update our content

6.2 You can block or erase cookies from your computer if you want to (your browser’s help screen or manual should tell you how to do this), but certain parts of the Site are reliant on the use of cookies to operate correctly and may not work correctly if you set your browser not to accept cookies.

7 Information about other products and services

7.1 From time to time we may send you information about our services which we think may be of interest to you if you are registered with My-TRIP.

7.2 You can tell us to stop this at any time by sending an e-mail to [jon.brassey@tripdatabase.com](mailto:jon.brassey@tripdatabase.com)

8 Security  
We have implemented technology and policies to safeguard your privacy from unauthorised access and improper use

9 Linking to third party websites

9.1 We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our Site and recommend that you check the policy of each site you visit and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.

9.2 In addition, if you linked to this Site from a third party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners or operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.

10 Transferring your information outside of Europe

10.1 [As part of the services offered to you through the Site, the information you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside of the European Union (“EU”). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU or one of our service providers is located in a country outside of the EU. We also share information between our group companies, which are located in countries worldwide. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this privacy policy.]

10.2 If you use our services while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU in order to provide you with those services.

11 Contact us

If at any time you would like to contact us with your views about our privacy practices, or with any enquiry relating to your personal information, you can do so by sending an e-mail to us at [jon.brassey@tripdatabase.com](mailto:jon.brassey@tripdatabase.com)  or write to us at Jon Brassey Trip Database Limited, little Maristowe, Glasllwch Lane, Newport, NP20 3PS

**UBM MEDICA PUBLISHER AGREEMENT PRIVACY GUIDELINES AND FAQS**

**WHAT PRIVACY RESPONSIBILITIES DOES A PUBLISHER HAVE AS A MEMBER OF THE MEDICA NETWORK?**

The Agreement you signed to become a Network Member includes two simple requirements regarding web site privacy:  As a Member, you have agreed to:

1\. Publish your own privacy policy explaining what information you collect from people who visit your web sites(s), how you use that data and what choices people have.  Your policy must meet recognized best practices, for example, be available by link published in the footer or each page on your site and elsewhere as appropriate.  You agree to abide by your policy and update it if your practices change and to provide Medica with a working link.

2\. Separately, publish the link to the Medica Network Privacy Policy in the footer of each page on your site(s).  Medica will provide the link to you.

You can find these two requirements in Section B.9 of the Agreement.

The Medica Network Privacy Policy provides notice of the advertising being displayed on your site and that Medica may use registration data for its own purposes.  Both privacy policies, taken together, describe what information is collected – by you, by third party ad servers and advertisers, and by Medica  – from people as they visit your site(s).

**WHY ARE THERE TWO SEPARATE PRIVACY POLICIES?**

Online advertising, particularly online behavioral advertising or OBA, continues to draw scrutiny from regulators.  Industry has responded with self-regulatory standards about notice and consent, including detailed provisions in privacy policies.  The ad serving disclosures are a significant part of the Network Policy.

Publishers could indeed include both the online advertising and other network disclosures within their privacy policies.  The challenge, though, is that ad servers may change across the network, as Medica makes ad sales on your behalf.  A separate Network Policy allows updates across the Network.  Medica doesn’t have to send you (and all network publishers) a notice and ask you to update that portion of your policy every time a change in advertising parties takes place.  We have more flexibility to arrange sales on your behalf.

**WHY DOES A PUBLISHER HAVE TO POST BOTH LINKS ON ITS HOME PAGE? WOULDN’T IT WORK JUST TO LINK TO THE NETWORK POLICY FROM WITHIN THE PUBLISHER’S POLICY?**

That is a really good question.

Medica requires a Network member to give the Network Policy equal standing to its own privacy policies because of the importance of the advertising disclosures.  Linking to a notice within a notice buries the information yet another level, a placement not consistent with industry standards. A FINAL NOTE

You are the only one that can assess and reflect your own data collection practices in your privacy policy.  For that reason, Medica cannot review your privacy policy or advise you on its accuracy or completeness.

Privacy is an important value amongst medical professionals.  The Medica Network is committed to high levels of transparency and privacy best practice as it serves those communities.  We ask Network members to share in that commitment.

<http://imaging.ubmmedica.com/all/UBMMedica%20Network_Privacy_Statement.html>
